<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "https://bugzilla.redhat.com/page.cgi?id=bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="4.4.12068.1"
          urlbase="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/"
          
          maintainer="bugzilla-error-list@redhat.com"
>

    <bug>
          <bug_id>1353445</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2016-07-07 02:18:00 -0400</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>No Jabber and SIP support included anymore?</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2016-07-12 11:01:46 -0400</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>2</classification_id>
          <classification>Fedora</classification>
          <product>Fedora</product>
          <component>gnome-online-accounts</component>
          <version>24</version>
          <rep_platform>x86_64</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Linux</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>ERRATA</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc></bug_file_loc>
          <status_whiteboard></status_whiteboard>
          <keywords></keywords>
          <priority>unspecified</priority>
          <bug_severity>medium</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Kees de Jong">keesdejong+bugs</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Debarshi Ray">debarshir</assigned_to>
          <cc>debarshir</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Fedora Extras Quality Assurance">extras-qa</qa_contact>
          
          <cf_fixed_in>gnome-online-accounts-3.20.2-1.fc24</cf_fixed_in>
          <cf_doc_type>If docs needed, set a value</cf_doc_type>
          <cf_release_notes></cf_release_notes>
          <cf_story_points>---</cf_story_points>
          
          <cf_environment></cf_environment>
          <cf_last_closed>2016-07-12 11:01:46</cf_last_closed>
          <cf_type>Bug</cf_type>
          <cf_regression_status>---</cf_regression_status>
          <cf_mount_type>---</cf_mount_type>
          <cf_documentation_action>---</cf_documentation_action>
          <cf_crm></cf_crm>
          <cf_verified_branch></cf_verified_branch>
          <cf_category>---</cf_category>
          <cf_ovirt_team>---</cf_ovirt_team>
          
          <cf_cloudforms_team>---</cf_cloudforms_team>
          
          
          
          
          <target_release>---</target_release>
          
          <votes>0</votes>

      

      

      

          <comment_sort_order>oldest_to_newest</comment_sort_order>  
          <long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>9486171</commentid>
    <comment_count>0</comment_count>
    <who name="Kees de Jong">keesdejong+bugs</who>
    <bug_when>2016-07-07 02:18:31 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>Description of problem: On Fedora 23 there was Jabber and SIP support by default included in the package. In the package description these components are still mentioned, but are not listed in the gnome-online-accounts options. 


Version-Release number of selected component (if applicable): gnome-online-accounts-3.20.1-1.fc24.x86_64


How reproducible: Open &quot;All Settings&quot; --&gt; &quot;Online Accounts&quot; --&gt; Click the + symbol --&gt; And there is no SIP or Jabber (XMPP) option listed anymore by default.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>9486245</commentid>
    <comment_count>1</comment_count>
    <who name="Kees de Jong">keesdejong+bugs</who>
    <bug_when>2016-07-07 03:04:05 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>An `rpm -ql gnome-online-accounts` on a Fedora 23 does display icons for Google Talk and more, it&apos;s also listed on the Gnome 3.20 release list: https://mail.gnome.org/archives/ftp-release-list/2016-March/msg00212.html
But not on Fedora 24.

So is it really not included in F24, if so why? Or are these extra&apos;s packaged in another package?</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>9490552</commentid>
    <comment_count>2</comment_count>
    <who name="Debarshi Ray">debarshir</who>
    <bug_when>2016-07-08 06:08:20 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>Chat support has been disabled in Fedora 24. See:
http://pkgs.fedoraproject.org/cgit/rpms/gnome-online-accounts.git/commit/?id=a4f03c0fc2a23f8a036c759498b0a64d71825ffc

We should update the RPM&apos;s description to reflect this.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>9490594</commentid>
    <comment_count>3</comment_count>
    <who name="Kees de Jong">keesdejong+bugs</who>
    <bug_when>2016-07-08 06:27:40 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>Fair enough, but I don&apos;t see why it was removed. The description of the commit and the minutes of the workstation work group don&apos;t discuss why it should be removed other than that Empathy is the only application using the Telepathy framework.

Single sign on seems to be &apos;broken&apos; now, since you have to sign on on Google for a second time to get the Google Talk application working (in Empathy, which isn&apos;t installed by default). And aren&apos;t other Jabber related configurations also online accounts?

I&apos;m just trying to understand why something is broken up in two places while it worked very well being in one single place, which makes it easy to configure and maintain.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>9490689</commentid>
    <comment_count>4</comment_count>
    <who name="Debarshi Ray">debarshir</who>
    <bug_when>2016-07-08 07:12:07 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>(In reply to K. de Jong from comment #3)
&gt; Fair enough, but I don&apos;t see why it was removed. The description of the
&gt; commit and the minutes of the workstation work group don&apos;t discuss why it
&gt; should be removed other than that Empathy is the only application using the
&gt; Telepathy framework.

Empathy is also the only chat application to have ever integrated with gnome-online-accounts. It is also very weekly maintained nowadays and don&apos;t support most of the popular networks these days - Telegram and Facebook come to mind.

&gt; Single sign on seems to be &apos;broken&apos; now, since you have to sign on on Google
&gt; for a second time to get the Google Talk application working (in Empathy,
&gt; which isn&apos;t installed by default). And aren&apos;t other Jabber related
&gt; configurations also online accounts?

I don&apos;t understand. What do you mean?</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>9490715</commentid>
    <comment_count>5</comment_count>
    <who name="Fedora Update System">updates</who>
    <bug_when>2016-07-08 07:27:20 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>gnome-online-accounts-3.20.2-1.fc24 has been submitted as an update to Fedora 24. https://bodhi.fedoraproject.org/updates/FEDORA-2016-ecaaeb9da2</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>9490773</commentid>
    <comment_count>6</comment_count>
    <who name="Kees de Jong">keesdejong+bugs</who>
    <bug_when>2016-07-08 07:46:00 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>(In reply to Debarshi Ray from comment #4)
&gt; (In reply to K. de Jong from comment #3)
&gt; &gt; Single sign on seems to be &apos;broken&apos; now, since you have to sign on on Google
&gt; &gt; for a second time to get the Google Talk application working (in Empathy,
&gt; &gt; which isn&apos;t installed by default). And aren&apos;t other Jabber related
&gt; &gt; configurations also online accounts?
&gt; 
&gt; I don&apos;t understand. What do you mean?

When Google is added in the gnome-online-accounts it lacks the Google Talk option (because that functionality is removed from the spec file and thus the build). To get Google Talk working a user needs to install Empathy and there too have to enter the Google credentials. If that user has two-step authentication enabled it&apos;s needed to create an application specific password(1) for Empathy to log in. With the previous available single-sign-on functionality (Fedora 23) in gnome-online-accounts this wasn&apos;t needed, a user could simply use the Google Authenticator to finish the two-step authentication.

This is what I mean with &apos;broken&apos; single-sign-on, because it&apos;s not a single sign on action anymore in Fedora 24 for e.g. Google, it&apos;s now in 2 places with their own login procedure. The gnome-online-accounts is also not a &apos;one-stop-shop&apos; anymore to configure and manage many of the online accounts (Jabber/SIP/etc.). For me it&apos;s hard to understand this breakup of functionality, it doesn&apos;t seem to add anything, in fact it makes things unnecessarily complicated.

1: https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/185833?hl=en</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>9491012</commentid>
    <comment_count>7</comment_count>
    <who name="Debarshi Ray">debarshir</who>
    <bug_when>2016-07-08 09:09:44 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>(In reply to K. de Jong from comment #6)
&gt; When Google is added in the gnome-online-accounts it lacks the Google Talk
&gt; option (because that functionality is removed from the spec file and thus
&gt; the build). To get Google Talk working a user needs to install Empathy and
&gt; there too have to enter the Google credentials. If that user has two-step
&gt; authentication enabled it&apos;s needed to create an application specific
&gt; password(1) for Empathy to log in. With the previous available
&gt; single-sign-on functionality (Fedora 23) in gnome-online-accounts this
&gt; wasn&apos;t needed, a user could simply use the Google Authenticator to finish
&gt; the two-step authentication.
&gt; 
&gt; This is what I mean with &apos;broken&apos; single-sign-on, because it&apos;s not a single
&gt; sign on action anymore in Fedora 24 for e.g. Google, it&apos;s now in 2 places
&gt; with their own login procedure. The gnome-online-accounts is also not a
&gt; &apos;one-stop-shop&apos; anymore to configure and manage many of the online accounts
&gt; (Jabber/SIP/etc.). For me it&apos;s hard to understand this breakup of
&gt; functionality, it doesn&apos;t seem to add anything, in fact it makes things
&gt; unnecessarily complicated.

This &quot;breakup&quot; of functionality is because we no longer have a good quality instant messaging client that integrates with gnome-online-accounts. There is no point in letting people create accounts for which they won&apos;t have an application by default.

As I mentioned in comment 4, empathy is very weekly maintained these days and haven&apos;t kept up with the times. These days most people either use standalone desktop clients or the web browser. We can re-enable the integration if we have a good enough application in future. Until then you&apos;ll have to install empathy yourself and set things up separately.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>9494511</commentid>
    <comment_count>8</comment_count>
    <who name="Fedora Update System">updates</who>
    <bug_when>2016-07-10 11:58:09 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>gnome-online-accounts-3.20.2-1.fc24 has been pushed to the Fedora 24 testing repository. If problems still persist, please make note of it in this bug report.
See https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/QA:Updates_Testing for
instructions on how to install test updates.
You can provide feedback for this update here: https://bodhi.fedoraproject.org/updates/FEDORA-2016-ecaaeb9da2</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>9501905</commentid>
    <comment_count>9</comment_count>
    <who name="Fedora Update System">updates</who>
    <bug_when>2016-07-12 11:01:44 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>gnome-online-accounts-3.20.2-1.fc24 has been pushed to the Fedora 24 stable repository. If problems still persist, please make note of it in this bug report.</thetext>
  </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>

</bugzilla>