<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "https://bugzilla.redhat.com/page.cgi?id=bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="4.4.12068.1"
          urlbase="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/"
          
          maintainer="bugzilla-error-list@redhat.com"
>

    <bug>
          <bug_id>1372582</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2016-09-02 02:32:00 -0400</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Can&apos;t load plugin &quot;kdevpythonsupport&quot;. Parsers for Python (and probably others like PHP) not working.</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2016-09-16 08:48:42 -0400</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>2</classification_id>
          <classification>Fedora</classification>
          <product>Fedora</product>
          <component>kdevelop</component>
          <version>24</version>
          <rep_platform>x86_64</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Linux</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>CURRENTRELEASE</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc></bug_file_loc>
          <status_whiteboard></status_whiteboard>
          <keywords></keywords>
          <priority>medium</priority>
          <bug_severity>medium</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="PARIJATHA KUMAR PASUPULETI">parijathakumar</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Rex Dieter">rdieter</assigned_to>
          <cc>helio</cc>
    
    
    <cc>jgrulich</cc>
    
    
    <cc>kde-sig</cc>
    
    
    <cc>parijathakumar</cc>
    
    
    <cc>rdieter</cc>
    
    
    <cc>rnovacek</cc>
    
    
    <cc>smparrish</cc>
    
    
    <cc>than</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Fedora Extras Quality Assurance">extras-qa</qa_contact>
          
          <cf_fixed_in></cf_fixed_in>
          <cf_doc_type>If docs needed, set a value</cf_doc_type>
          <cf_release_notes></cf_release_notes>
          <cf_story_points>---</cf_story_points>
          
          <cf_environment></cf_environment>
          <cf_last_closed>2016-09-16 08:48:42</cf_last_closed>
          <cf_type>---</cf_type>
          <cf_regression_status>---</cf_regression_status>
          <cf_mount_type>---</cf_mount_type>
          <cf_documentation_action>---</cf_documentation_action>
          <cf_crm></cf_crm>
          <cf_verified_branch></cf_verified_branch>
          <cf_category>---</cf_category>
          <cf_ovirt_team>---</cf_ovirt_team>
          
          <cf_cloudforms_team>---</cf_cloudforms_team>
          
          
          
          
          <target_release>---</target_release>
          
          <votes>0</votes>

      

      

      

          <comment_sort_order>oldest_to_newest</comment_sort_order>  
          <long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>9674118</commentid>
    <comment_count>0</comment_count>
    <who name="PARIJATHA KUMAR PASUPULETI">parijathakumar</who>
    <bug_when>2016-09-02 02:32:56 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>User-Agent:       Mozilla/5.0 (X11; Linux x86_64) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/53.0.2785.89 Safari/537.36
Build Identifier: 

I felt lack of Python support in KDevelop. Parsers are not working. I could not see &apos;Python Style Checking&apos; and &apos;Python Documentation&apos; entries in KDevelop settings which made me suspect that something is amiss. Then when I ran KDevelop from terminal to see the cause, I got the following error which has confirmed that Python support is not loaded in my KDevelop. The error is &quot;Can&apos;t load plugin &quot;kdevpythonsupport&quot; because a factory to load the plugin could not be obtained: &quot;Cannot load library /usr/lib64/qt5/plugins/kdevplatform/25/kdevpythonlanguagesupport.so: (/lib64/libkdevpythonduchain.so: undefined symbol: _ZN8KDevelop16BackgroundParser11addDocumentERKNS_13IndexedStringENS_12TopDUContext8FeaturesEiP7QObject6QFlagsINS_8ParseJob24SequentialProcessingFlagEE)&quot;.

I&apos;ve removed KDevelop completely (including kdevelop-python), checked for any stale libraries in my system with &apos; find / -name &quot;*kdev*.so*&quot; &apos;. After confirming there are no stray libraries left, I&apos;ve cleaned my package cache, and reinstalled KDevelop again along with kdevelop-python. But still the same problem persists.

I am Fedora-24 KDE spin. I don&apos;t have any testing repos enabled.

Reproducible: Always

Steps to Reproduce:
1.Install kdevelop and kdevelop-python
2.Run kdevelop from terminal or from applications menu.
3.In the kdevelop settings, go to &apos;Plugins&apos; and enable &apos;Python Support&apos;
Actual Results:  
Not able to see the two entries in kdevelop settings ... &apos;Python Style Checking&apos; and &apos;Python Documentation&apos;. Custom include/import paths in project configuration (right click on the project, then &apos;Open Configuration&apos;) are not working. KDevelop still complains about undefined variables which reference to the custom include paths.

Expected Results:  
Python parsers should work. You should see two entries in kdevelop settings ... &apos;Python Style Checking&apos; and &apos;Python Documentation&apos;. Also, give custom include/import paths in project configuration (right click on the project, then &apos;Open Configuration&apos;). The custom imports should work. KDevelop should not complain about undefined variables which reference to your custom include paths.

I&apos;ve reported to KDevelop developers in IRC and Forums. They told it must be something to do with &quot;library version mismatch between the Python pluigin (which is a separate package!) and kdevplatform&quot;.

The AppImage from KDevelop website works fine without any issues.

Also, some one else has reported in IRC that PHP parsers are also not working in the Fedora&apos;s repo&apos;s KDevelop package and the included kdevelop-php packages.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>9674172</commentid>
    <comment_count>1</comment_count>
    <who name="Jan Grulich">jgrulich</who>
    <bug_when>2016-09-02 02:53:52 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>There will be soon the final version of KDevelop 5 available for Fedora 24 which I guess will fix this problem. If you want it sooner you would need to enable updates-testing repository to get it as soon as possible.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>9674203</commentid>
    <comment_count>2</comment_count>
    <who name="PARIJATHA KUMAR PASUPULETI">parijathakumar</who>
    <bug_when>2016-09-02 03:09:21 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>(In reply to Jan Grulich from comment #1)
&gt; There will be soon the final version of KDevelop 5 available for Fedora 24
&gt; which I guess will fix this problem. If you want it sooner you would need to
&gt; enable updates-testing repository to get it as soon as possible.

I am afraid that may not solve the problem. I&apos;ve tried with &apos;sudo dnf --enablerepo=updates-testing upgrade kdevelop&apos;. But still the problem persisted. May be we need a compatible kdevelop-python update also.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>9696005</commentid>
    <comment_count>3</comment_count>
    <who name="PARIJATHA KUMAR PASUPULETI">parijathakumar</who>
    <bug_when>2016-09-10 05:29:59 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>Today, the said update landed. As I&apos;ve suspected, the problem still persists with the latest version of KDevelop 5. Python support still does not work. I am not able to see the two entries in KDevelop settings ... &apos;Python Style Checking&apos; and &apos;Python Documentation&apos;. Because of this my PEP8 checking does not work. No errors/warnings/info messages are shown. I can not comment on custom imports immediately. I&apos;ll check and write back.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>9696068</commentid>
    <comment_count>4</comment_count>
    <who name="Helio Chissini de Castro">helio</who>
    <bug_when>2016-09-10 06:36:43 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>kdevelop php was submitted yesterday to stable in f24. Python still need some polish.

Apologizes for the delay.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>9696134</commentid>
    <comment_count>5</comment_count>
    <who name="Rex Dieter">rdieter</who>
    <bug_when>2016-09-10 08:56:30 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>I&apos;ll be refreshing the kdevelop stack soon along with kdepim-16.08.x landing at the same time (due to some common dependencies between them)</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>9713898</commentid>
    <comment_count>6</comment_count>
    <who name="PARIJATHA KUMAR PASUPULETI">parijathakumar</who>
    <bug_when>2016-09-16 06:23:53 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>The said updates landed today. I&apos;ve just updated my system. But still the python parsers in custom include paths are not working. At least, I can see python support in KDevelop settings now. That problem is settled. But then I am not able to figure out why the parsing does not work for the custom include paths I gave in the project configuration ? Do I need to clean some cache or something ?</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>9714340</commentid>
    <comment_count>7</comment_count>
    <who name="PARIJATHA KUMAR PASUPULETI">parijathakumar</who>
    <bug_when>2016-09-16 08:48:42 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>So, I&apos;ve removed kdevelop and kdevelop-pthon packages completely, then &apos;dnf clean all&apos;, &apos;dnf distro-sync&apos;, and reinstalled. Also, I&apos;ve removed any old configuration files from my home directory. Now, every thing is working fine.

Thanks for the support. I am closing the ticket.</thetext>
  </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>

</bugzilla>