<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "https://bugzilla.redhat.com/page.cgi?id=bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="4.4.12068.1"
          urlbase="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/"
          
          maintainer="bugzilla-error-list@redhat.com"
>

    <bug>
          <bug_id>1409121</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2016-12-29 11:57:00 -0500</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>candidate characters displayed using too small font size.</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2017-04-13 03:14:11 -0400</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>2</classification_id>
          <classification>Fedora</classification>
          <product>Fedora</product>
          <component>ibus-pinyin</component>
          <version>24</version>
          <rep_platform>x86_64</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Linux</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>CURRENTRELEASE</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc></bug_file_loc>
          <status_whiteboard></status_whiteboard>
          <keywords></keywords>
          <priority>unspecified</priority>
          <bug_severity>medium</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Bill">mattison.computer</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Peng Wu">pwu</assigned_to>
          <cc>i18n-bugs</cc>
    
    
    <cc>mattison.computer</cc>
    
    
    <cc>pwu</cc>
    
    
    <cc>shawn.p.huang</cc>
          <qa_contact name="Fedora Extras Quality Assurance">extras-qa</qa_contact>
          
          <cf_fixed_in></cf_fixed_in>
          <cf_doc_type>If docs needed, set a value</cf_doc_type>
          <cf_release_notes></cf_release_notes>
          <cf_story_points>---</cf_story_points>
          
          <cf_environment></cf_environment>
          <cf_last_closed>2017-04-13 03:14:11</cf_last_closed>
          <cf_type>Bug</cf_type>
          <cf_regression_status>---</cf_regression_status>
          <cf_mount_type>---</cf_mount_type>
          <cf_documentation_action>---</cf_documentation_action>
          <cf_crm></cf_crm>
          <cf_verified_branch></cf_verified_branch>
          <cf_category>---</cf_category>
          <cf_ovirt_team>---</cf_ovirt_team>
          
          <cf_cloudforms_team>---</cf_cloudforms_team>
          
          
          
          
          <target_release>---</target_release>
          
          <votes>0</votes>

      

      

      

          <comment_sort_order>oldest_to_newest</comment_sort_order>  
          <long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>10024258</commentid>
    <comment_count>0</comment_count>
    <who name="Bill">mattison.computer</who>
    <bug_when>2016-12-29 11:57:59 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Description of problem:

1. In Gnome, when using ibus to enter simplified Chinese characters, candidate characters are displayed using a font size that is too small to distinguish the characters consisting of a larger number of strokes.  This makes it very difficult to find, recognize, and distinguish many characters, and to select the correct one matching the entered pinyin.  Characters with a large number of strokes are somewhat fuzzy.

2. In Gnome, I cannot find a way to set or change the font used to display candidate characters.  It would help if I could set both the font type and the font size.  This is basically the problem reported in Bugzilla #956512.  (I find that the &quot;AR PL UKai&quot; (regular) font characters are significantly easier to recognize, distinguish, and read than the &quot;AR UL UMing&quot;, &quot;Wen QuanYi&quot;, Song, Ming, and sans-serif fonts, but I cannot get the characters menus to be displayed using &quot;AR PL UKai&quot; fonts.)

3. In KDE Plasma, a mix of fonts is used to display candidate characters for the entered pinyin spelling.


Version-Release number of selected component (if applicable):
(how do I determine this?)


How reproducible:

By trying to use ibus to enter simplified Chinese characters into a Libre Office document or a simple vi (or vim) text file.


Steps to Reproduce:

1. In Gnome, launch Libre Office or vi (or vim).  Activate ibus for entry of simplified Chinese characters.  Try entering a complicated Chinese character by typing in its pinyin spelling.  Examples include the second character of the names of the Xinjiang, Xizang, and Anhui provinces.

2. In KDE Plasma, try the same thing.


Actual results:

1. The characters in the menu of characters matching the entered pinyin are small.  The more complicated characters in the menu of characters matching &quot;jiang&quot;, &quot;zang&quot;, and &quot;hui&quot; are fuzzy and difficult to distinguish and recognize.

2. Varying fonts are used to display the characters in the menu of characters matching the entered pinyin.


Expected results:

1. Characters in the menu of characters matching the entered pinyin should be displayed in a larger font so that even the complex characters can be easily distinguished and recognized.

2. The same font should be used to display all characters in the menu of characters matching the entered pinyin.


Additional info:

A. I also ask that ibus give me a way (in all desktop managers) of setting the font type and size used to display characters in the menu of characters matching the entered pinyin.

B. I am not fluent in Chinese, but am trying to learn simplified Chinese.  I do use simplified Chinese sometimes, and use ibus for entering simplified Chinese into docs, text files, and e-mail.  I am having serious problems entering the more complicated characters because of the issues reported in this bug.  It&apos;s costing me a lot of time.  Please fix!

C. I do not know if these problems also occur when entering traditional Chinese or other eastern Asian languages (like Japanese).

D. I do not know how to capture an image of ibus&apos;s menu of characters matching the entered pinyin.  If would like an image, tell me how, and I&apos;ll try it.  Note: I do not have a portable device (e.g. iphone) that can take pictures.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>10029458</commentid>
    <comment_count>1</comment_count>
    <who name="Peng Wu">pwu</who>
    <bug_when>2017-01-03 00:14:11 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>For GNOME, please install this extension, and run ibus-setup to change the font size.
URL: https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/1121/ibus-font-setting/

For KDE, please try ibus-setup.
If ibus-setup doesn&apos;t work, please open another bug for it, thanks!</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>10332007</commentid>
    <comment_count>2</comment_count>
    <who name="Peng Wu">pwu</who>
    <bug_when>2017-04-13 03:14:11 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>For mix of fonts, please try fonts-tweak-tool to adjust it.

Close bug.</thetext>
  </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>

</bugzilla>