<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "https://bugzilla.redhat.com/page.cgi?id=bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="4.4.12068.1" urlbase="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/" maintainer="bugzilla-error-list@redhat.com">

  <bug>
    <bug_id>1229218</bug_id>

    <creation_ts>2015-06-08 05:41:00 -0400</creation_ts>
    <short_desc>Conflicting default keyboard shortcuts</short_desc>
    <delta_ts>2016-07-24 11:02:56 -0400</delta_ts>
    <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
    <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
    <classification_id>2</classification_id>
    <classification>Fedora</classification>
    <product>Fedora</product>
    <component>libxfce4ui</component>
    <version>24</version>
    <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
    <op_sys>Linux</op_sys>
    <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
    <resolution>RAWHIDE</resolution>

    <bug_file_loc></bug_file_loc>
    <status_whiteboard></status_whiteboard>
    <keywords>Reopened</keywords>
    <priority>unspecified</priority>
    <bug_severity>low</bug_severity>
    <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>

    <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
    <reporter name="Laurentiu Pancescu">lpancescu</reporter>
    <assigned_to name="Kevin Fenzi">kevin</assigned_to>
    <cc>cwickert</cc>

    <cc>kevin</cc>

    <cc>nonamedotc</cc>
    <qa_contact name="Fedora Extras Quality Assurance">extras-qa</qa_contact>

    <cf_fixed_in></cf_fixed_in>
  <cf_doc_type>Bug Fix</cf_doc_type>
<cf_release_notes></cf_release_notes>
<cf_story_points>---</cf_story_points>

<cf_environment></cf_environment>
<cf_last_closed>2016-07-24 11:02:56</cf_last_closed>
<cf_type>Bug</cf_type>
<cf_regression_status>---</cf_regression_status>
<cf_mount_type>---</cf_mount_type>
<cf_documentation_action>---</cf_documentation_action>
<cf_crm></cf_crm>
<cf_verified_branch></cf_verified_branch>
<cf_category>---</cf_category>
<cf_ovirt_team>---</cf_ovirt_team>

<cf_cloudforms_team>---</cf_cloudforms_team>
<external_bugs name="Xfce">11979</external_bugs>

<target_release>---</target_release>

<votes>0</votes>

<comment_sort_order>oldest_to_newest</comment_sort_order>
<long_desc isprivate="0">
<commentid>8313793</commentid>
<comment_count>0</comment_count>
<who name="Laurentiu Pancescu">lpancescu</who>
<bug_when>2015-06-08 05:41:41 -0400</bug_when>
<thetext>Description of problem: The XFCE default keyboard shortcuts in Fedora 22 bind Ctrl-Alt-L to both &quot;show the logout dialog&quot; (xfce4-session-logout) and &quot;lock the screen&quot; (xflock4). Version-Release number of selected
component (if applicable): 4.12.0-5.fc22 How reproducible: Always Steps to Reproduce: 1. Press Ctrl-Alt-L Actual results: The system either locks the screen or shows the logout dialog. Which of the two happens seems to be randomly selected at login.
Expected results: The system always shows the logout dialog, like in Fedora 21 and previous versions. Additional info: The workaround is to delete the Ctrl-Alt-L binding from xflock4, using xfce4-keyboard-settings, and then login again (the removal
doesn&apos;t seem to apply before logout).</thetext>
</long_desc>
<long_desc isprivate="0">
<commentid>8324005</commentid>
<comment_count>1</comment_count>
<who name="Kevin Fenzi">kevin</who>
<bug_when>2015-06-10 16:10:54 -0400</bug_when>
<thetext>I can confirm there&apos;s something odd going on here, I just haven&apos;t had time to dig into it yet. Here when I &apos;reset to defaults&apos; I actually get 2 xflock4 entries... one with control-alt-delete and one with control-alt-l. ;(
I&apos;ll try and track it down, or you are welcome to file an upstream bug to see if they can find it sooner.</thetext>
</long_desc>
<long_desc isprivate="0">
<commentid>8324280</commentid>
<comment_count>2</comment_count>
<who name="Laurentiu Pancescu">lpancescu</who>
<bug_when>2015-06-10 18:25:26 -0400</bug_when>
<thetext>It seems that xfce4-settings gets its defaults from libxfce4kbd-private (part of libxfce4ui, where they are stored in the xfce4-keyboard-shortcuts.xml file). The conflicting keyboard shortcut was added by upstream last summer [1], after an
enhancement request [2]. Should I file a bug directly in the XFCE Bugzilla? [1] http://git.xfce.org/xfce/libxfce4ui/commit/libxfce4kbd-private/xfce4-keyboard-shortcuts.xml?id=635521fe76d5969d49f2da98a8013e32fa394848 [2]
https://bugzilla.xfce.org/show_bug.cgi?id=10728</thetext>
</long_desc>
<long_desc isprivate="0">
<commentid>8327176</commentid>
<comment_count>3</comment_count>
<who name="Kevin Fenzi">kevin</who>
<bug_when>2015-06-11 11:02:50 -0400</bug_when>
<thetext>Ah, it seems that we are carrying a Fedora specific patch that adds the shortcut for control-alt-l showing the logout dialog. ;( I&apos;ll have to dig into history and see why we added this and didn&apos;t try and upstream it, but it leaves
us in a bad place. Do we drop our control-alt-l for logout in favor of the now upstreamed xfce4-lock shortcut? Or do we try and get upstream to change?</thetext>
</long_desc>
<long_desc isprivate="0">
<commentid>8327683</commentid>
<comment_count>4</comment_count>
<who name="Laurentiu Pancescu">lpancescu</who>
<bug_when>2015-06-11 12:28:53 -0400</bug_when>
<thetext>Consistency with Gnome apparently played a role in upstream&apos;s acceptance of that enhancement request, but I&apos;m not sure to which extent they actively try to follow Gnome. There is only some overlap with the current Gnome3 keyboard
shortcuts [1], but less than during Gnome 2, and Gnome 3 dropped many of their Ctrl+Alt shortcuts in favor of Super+, e.g. Ctrl+Alt+L became Super+L for locking the screen (just like Windows 2000, if I remember correctly, and probably easier to
type). I think Ctrl+Alt+Del produced a multiple-button dialog in Windows, similar to the logout dialog in XFCE; in Gnome 3, that shows the poweroff dialog, but their wiki mentions changing that to Super+F4. [2] I think a shortcut for the logoff
dialog is nice, whatever that may be (as long as there is one). Probably Super+L to lock the screen and Ctrl+Alt+Del to logout would be the most similar to both Gnome and Windows, assuming the upstream wants to change anything at all. [1]
https://help.gnome.org/users/gnome-help/stable/keyboard-shortcuts-set.html.en [2] https://wiki.gnome.org/Design/OS/KeyboardShortcuts</thetext>
</long_desc>
<long_desc isprivate="0">
<commentid>8328448</commentid>
<comment_count>5</comment_count>
<who name="Kevin Fenzi">kevin</who>
<bug_when>2015-06-11 15:00:49 -0400</bug_when>
<thetext>Would you be willing to file an upstream bug explaining things? Otherwise I can do so this weekend...</thetext>
</long_desc>
<long_desc isprivate="0">
<commentid>8329817</commentid>
<comment_count>6</comment_count>
<who name="Laurentiu Pancescu">lpancescu</who>
<bug_when>2015-06-12 03:49:03 -0400</bug_when>
<thetext>Opened upstream bug #11979: https://bugzilla.xfce.org/show_bug.cgi?id=11979</thetext>
</long_desc>
<long_desc isprivate="0">
<commentid>9528987</commentid>
<comment_count>7</comment_count>
<who name="Fedora End Of Life">jkurik</who>
<bug_when>2016-07-19 16:10:10 -0400</bug_when>
<thetext>Fedora 22 changed to end-of-life (EOL) status on 2016-07-19. Fedora 22 is no longer maintained, which means that it will not receive any further security or bug fix updates. As a result we are closing this bug. If you can reproduce this bug
against a currently maintained version of Fedora please feel free to reopen this bug against that version. If you are unable to reopen this bug, please file a new report against the current release. If you experience problems, please add a comment to
this bug. Thank you for reporting this bug and we are sorry it could not be fixed.</thetext>
</long_desc>
<long_desc isprivate="0">
<commentid>9537969</commentid>
<comment_count>8</comment_count>
<who name="Laurentiu Pancescu">lpancescu</who>
<bug_when>2016-07-21 13:55:02 -0400</bug_when>
<thetext>The issue is still valid in Fedora 23 and 24, since nothing has changed in the Fedora-specific patch. The fix would be trivial, given a decision about the extra shortcuts. Unfortunately, there has been no reaction from upstream until now -
it&apos;s probably unlikely that they&apos;ll still answer. I would also be ok with not having any key shortcut for logging out, since it&apos;s not something I do that often and it would be consistent with upstream (one can also use Alt-F1
&lt;UpArrow&gt; &lt;Enter&gt; to trigger the logout dialog, or the power button, if configured like this in xfce4-power-manager).</thetext>
</long_desc>
<long_desc isprivate="0">
<commentid>9543430</commentid>
<comment_count>9</comment_count>
<who name="Kevin Fenzi">kevin</who>
<bug_when>2016-07-23 20:15:42 -0400</bug_when>
<thetext>ok, lets just drop the logout one. I&apos;ve now built that in rawhide. Do you want it in stable releases as well?</thetext>
</long_desc>
<long_desc isprivate="0">
<commentid>9543790</commentid>
<comment_count>10</comment_count>
<who name="Laurentiu Pancescu">lpancescu</who>
<bug_when>2016-07-24 00:56:24 -0400</bug_when>
<thetext>Not necessarily, it only affects the first login in XFCE (I normally restore the entire home directory from backups, so I seldom see it). Thanks! :)</thetext>
</long_desc>
<long_desc isprivate="0">
<commentid>9544213</commentid>
<comment_count>11</comment_count>
<who name="Kevin Fenzi">kevin</who>
<bug_when>2016-07-24 11:02:56 -0400</bug_when>
<thetext>ok. Let us know if you spot anything further here. Thanks for your patience.</thetext>
</long_desc>

</bug>

</bugzilla>
