<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "https://bugzilla.redhat.com/page.cgi?id=bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="4.4.12068.1" urlbase="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/" maintainer="bugzilla-error-list@redhat.com">

  <bug>
    <bug_id>1196287</bug_id>

    <creation_ts>2015-02-25 11:03:00 -0500</creation_ts>
    <short_desc>system-config-users doesn&apos;t allow assigning an existing group to a new user in the create user dialog</short_desc>
    <delta_ts>2016-10-14 06:49:20 -0400</delta_ts>
    <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
    <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
    <classification_id>2</classification_id>
    <classification>Fedora</classification>
    <product>Fedora</product>
    <component>system-config-users</component>
    <version>24</version>
    <rep_platform>Unspecified</rep_platform>
    <op_sys>Linux</op_sys>
    <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
    <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>

    <bug_file_loc></bug_file_loc>
    <status_whiteboard></status_whiteboard>
    <keywords>Reopened</keywords>
    <priority>unspecified</priority>
    <bug_severity>low</bug_severity>
    <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>

    <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
    <reporter name="Edgar Hoch">edgar.hoch</reporter>
    <assigned_to name="Nils Philippsen">nphilipp</assigned_to>
    <cc>nphilipp</cc>

    <cc>pnemade</cc>
    <qa_contact name="Fedora Extras Quality Assurance">extras-qa</qa_contact>

    <cf_fixed_in></cf_fixed_in>
  <cf_doc_type>Bug Fix</cf_doc_type>
<cf_release_notes></cf_release_notes>
<cf_story_points>---</cf_story_points>

<cf_environment></cf_environment>
<cf_last_closed>2016-10-14 06:49:20</cf_last_closed>
<cf_type>Bug</cf_type>
<cf_regression_status>---</cf_regression_status>
<cf_mount_type>---</cf_mount_type>
<cf_documentation_action>---</cf_documentation_action>
<cf_crm></cf_crm>
<cf_verified_branch></cf_verified_branch>
<cf_category>---</cf_category>
<cf_ovirt_team>---</cf_ovirt_team>

<cf_cloudforms_team>---</cf_cloudforms_team>

<target_release>---</target_release>

<votes>0</votes>

<comment_sort_order>oldest_to_newest</comment_sort_order>
<long_desc isprivate="0">
<commentid>7975909</commentid>
<comment_count>0</comment_count>
<who name="Edgar Hoch">edgar.hoch</who>
<bug_when>2015-02-25 11:03:24 -0500</bug_when>
<thetext>Description of problem: When creating an new user using system-config-users GUI, and I choose &quot;Specify group ID manually:&quot; and enter a gid for an already existing group, then I get the error message dialog &quot;The gid XXXX is
already in use.&quot; although I have deselected &quot;Create a private group for the user&quot;. Version-Release number of selected component (if applicable): system-config-users-1.3.6-1.fc21.noarch How reproducible: Always. Steps to Reproduce: 1.
Call system-config-users 2. Click on &quot;Add Group&quot; and create a new group. Remember the GID XXXX of this group. 3. Click on &quot;Add User&quot; 4. Fill out the form, deselct &quot;Create a private group for the user&quot;, select
&quot;Specify user ID manually:&quot; and enter an unused UID, select &quot;Specify group ID manually:&quot; and enter the GID XXXX of the group created in step 2. 5. Click on &quot;Ok&quot;. Actual results: Dialog box with the message &quot;The gid
XXXX is already in use.&quot; (where XXXX is the GID entered in step 4). Expected results: No error message. The user should be created with the default gid XXXX as entered in the form. Additional info: There is a workaround: Create a new user with
deselected &quot;Specify group ID manually:&quot; checkbox, and use the remaining values as in the steps described before. This should create a new user with the default group is &quot;users&quot;. Then select the new user in the summary, click on
&quot;Properties&quot;, select the tab &quot;Groups&quot;, select the (existing) group that the user should have as default group, and then deselect the group users (the order is important). Then click on &quot;Ok&quot;.</thetext>
</long_desc>
<long_desc isprivate="0">
<commentid>8787432</commentid>
<comment_count>1</comment_count>
<who name="Fedora End Of Life">jkurik</who>
<bug_when>2015-11-04 08:27:00 -0500</bug_when>
<thetext>This message is a reminder that Fedora 21 is nearing its end of life. Approximately 4 (four) weeks from now Fedora will stop maintaining and issuing updates for Fedora 21. It is Fedora&apos;s policy to close all bug reports from releases
that are no longer maintained. At that time this bug will be closed as EOL if it remains open with a Fedora &apos;version&apos; of &apos;21&apos;. Package Maintainer: If you wish for this bug to remain open because you plan to fix it in a currently
maintained version, simply change the &apos;version&apos; to a later Fedora version. Thank you for reporting this issue and we are sorry that we were not able to fix it before Fedora 21 is end of life. If you would still like to see this bug fixed
and are able to reproduce it against a later version of Fedora, you are encouraged change the &apos;version&apos; to a later Fedora version prior this bug is closed as described in the policy above. Although we aim to fix as many bugs as possible
during every release&apos;s lifetime, sometimes those efforts are overtaken by events. Often a more recent Fedora release includes newer upstream software that fixes bugs or makes them obsolete.</thetext>
</long_desc>
<long_desc isprivate="0">
<commentid>8787777</commentid>
<comment_count>2</comment_count>
<who name="Edgar Hoch">edgar.hoch</who>
<bug_when>2015-11-04 08:41:40 -0500</bug_when>
<thetext>The problem still exists on Fedora 22.</thetext>
</long_desc>
<long_desc isprivate="0">
<commentid>9528937</commentid>
<comment_count>3</comment_count>
<who name="Fedora End Of Life">jkurik</who>
<bug_when>2016-07-19 16:07:50 -0400</bug_when>
<thetext>Fedora 22 changed to end-of-life (EOL) status on 2016-07-19. Fedora 22 is no longer maintained, which means that it will not receive any further security or bug fix updates. As a result we are closing this bug. If you can reproduce this bug
against a currently maintained version of Fedora please feel free to reopen this bug against that version. If you are unable to reopen this bug, please file a new report against the current release. If you experience problems, please add a comment to
this bug. Thank you for reporting this bug and we are sorry it could not be fixed.</thetext>
</long_desc>
<long_desc isprivate="0">
<commentid>9529399</commentid>
<comment_count>4</comment_count>
<who name="Edgar Hoch">edgar.hoch</who>
<bug_when>2016-07-19 16:48:00 -0400</bug_when>
<thetext>The problem still exists on Fedora 24.</thetext>
</long_desc>
<long_desc isprivate="0">
<commentid>9791441</commentid>
<comment_count>5</comment_count>
<who name="Nils Philippsen">nphilipp</who>
<bug_when>2016-10-14 06:49:20 -0400</bug_when>
<thetext>I see this as a feature request. Unfortunately, I don&apos;t have the time to work on those anymore, considering I&apos;ve orphaned the system-config tools form F-25 on back in August:
https://lists.fedoraproject.org/archives/list/devel@lists.fedoraproject.org/message/BIV6Z2LN2LCO4I6LE636PPWOINUETV3S/ Therefore, I&apos;ll close this bug.</thetext>
</long_desc>

</bug>

</bugzilla>
