<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "https://bugzilla.redhat.com/page.cgi?id=bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="4.4.12068.1" urlbase="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/" maintainer="bugzilla-error-list@redhat.com">

  <bug>
    <bug_id>1350273</bug_id>

    <creation_ts>2016-06-26 19:05:00 -0400</creation_ts>
    <short_desc>gnome-software dependency on epiphany-runtime is unnecessary</short_desc>
    <delta_ts>2016-06-27 14:22:49 -0400</delta_ts>
    <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
    <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
    <classification_id>2</classification_id>
    <classification>Fedora</classification>
    <product>Fedora</product>
    <component>gnome-software</component>
    <version>24</version>
    <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
    <op_sys>Linux</op_sys>
    <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
    <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>

    <bug_file_loc></bug_file_loc>
    <status_whiteboard></status_whiteboard>
    <keywords></keywords>
    <priority>unspecified</priority>
    <bug_severity>unspecified</bug_severity>
    <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>

    <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
    <reporter name="Jeremy Bicha">jbicha</reporter>
    <assigned_to name="Richard Hughes">rhughes</assigned_to>
    <cc>gecko-bugs-nobody</cc>

    <cc>klember</cc>

    <cc>mcatanzaro</cc>

    <cc>rhughes</cc>

    <cc>rob.townley</cc>
    <qa_contact name="Fedora Extras Quality Assurance">extras-qa</qa_contact>

    <cf_fixed_in></cf_fixed_in>
  <cf_doc_type>If docs needed, set a value</cf_doc_type>
<cf_release_notes></cf_release_notes>
<cf_story_points>---</cf_story_points>

<cf_environment></cf_environment>
<cf_last_closed>2016-06-27 12:22:49</cf_last_closed>
<cf_type>Bug</cf_type>
<cf_regression_status>---</cf_regression_status>
<cf_mount_type>---</cf_mount_type>
<cf_documentation_action>---</cf_documentation_action>
<cf_crm></cf_crm>
<cf_verified_branch></cf_verified_branch>
<cf_category>---</cf_category>
<cf_ovirt_team>---</cf_ovirt_team>

<cf_cloudforms_team>---</cf_cloudforms_team>

<target_release>---</target_release>

<votes>0</votes>

<comment_sort_order>oldest_to_newest</comment_sort_order>
<long_desc isprivate="0">
<commentid>9453577</commentid>
<comment_count>0</comment_count>
<who name="Jeremy Bicha">jbicha</who>
<bug_when>2016-06-26 19:05:16 -0400</bug_when>
<thetext>Version-Release number of selected component (if applicable): tested with Fedora 24 although apparently this has been around for a while Description of problem: The Software app (gnome-software) has a dependency on epiphany-runtime for web
app integration. The problem is that epiphany-runtime includes all of Epiphany except that it doesn&apos;t include a .desktop or the GNOME Shell search provider. 1. Users may not even know they have Epiphany installed (perhaps someone doesn&apos;t
want to have Epiphany installed out of fear of potential security unmaintainability) 2. It&apos;s impossible for a user to add a web app for the Software app to manage unless the user runs Epiphany...which generally means the user needs the .desktop
The web app integration is a plugin. If epiphany is not installed, that plugin doesn&apos;t do anything but that&apos;s ok. The Software app still works. From the changelog: * Mon Feb 03 2014 Richard Hughes 1:3.11.3-2 - Split out a -runtime
subpackage to avoid making the gnome-software application depend on the epiphany application. Expected results: 1. I would like to see gnome-software not depend on epiphany(-runtime) 2. The current epiphany-runtime package doesn&apos;t make sense to
me. A GUI program shipped in a package should either include or at least depend on its .desktop. 3. Re-evaluate whether Fedora wants to ship 2 browsers by default for its GNOME Desktop.</thetext>
</long_desc>
<long_desc isprivate="0">
<commentid>9455714</commentid>
<comment_count>1</comment_count>
<who name="Michael Catanzaro">mcatanzaro</who>
<bug_when>2016-06-27 10:50:55 -0400</bug_when>
<thetext>The epiphany-runtime package currently exists only to support GNOME Software, but it will soon be required for the fedora-developer-portal RPM, so it will need to exist forever unless plans for fedora-developer-portal change. Anyway,
I&apos;ll move this bug over to the gnome-software maintainers. It seems like your request is for them to drop web app support, which seems like a tough sell to me, but I&apos;ll just *shrug* (In reply to Jeremy Bicha from comment #0) &gt; The
problem is that epiphany-runtime includes all of Epiphany except that it &gt; doesn&apos;t include a .desktop or the GNOME Shell search provider. &gt; 1. Users may not even know they have Epiphany installed So, to explain the background behind this:
that&apos;s exactly the point. We religiously follow Ubuntu&apos;s &quot;ship only one of each thing&quot; approach to default apps. But we want Firefox to be the default browser (which I obviously disagree with), and we can&apos;t actually remove
Epiphany if we want to support web apps (requirement for Software), so we&apos;re stuck with two. Best we can do is hide the desktop file and search provider to give the user the impression that only one is installed, and avoid cluttering menus with
a browser the user might not use. &gt; (perhaps someone &gt; doesn&apos;t want to have Epiphany installed out of fear of potential security &gt; unmaintainability) We usually get WebKit security updates in Fedora before they hit Apple devices, only
the security advisories are delayed until after the updates reach Apple users. It&apos;s a shame you don&apos;t take WebKit updates in Ubuntu, where this is a big problem, but that isn&apos;t relevant to Fedora. Anyway, WebKit is a dependency of
GNOME, so it will be installed regardless, and 99% of security bugs are there, not in Epiphany... so no problem here.</thetext>
</long_desc>
<long_desc isprivate="0">
<commentid>9455716</commentid>
<comment_count>2</comment_count>
<who name="Michael Catanzaro">mcatanzaro</who>
<bug_when>2016-06-27 10:51:26 -0400</bug_when>
<thetext>(In reply to Michael Catanzaro from comment #1) &gt; Anyway, I&apos;ll move this bug over to the gnome-software maintainers. (so they can decide whether to maintain the dependency on epiphany-runtime)</thetext>
</long_desc>
<long_desc isprivate="0">
<commentid>9456127</commentid>
<comment_count>3</comment_count>
<who name="Michael Catanzaro">mcatanzaro</who>
<bug_when>2016-06-27 12:22:49 -0400</bug_when>
<thetext>&gt; 1. I would like to see gnome-software not depend on epiphany(-runtime) I talked with Richard on IRC and he confirms that we want to keep the web app support working out of the box, so I&apos;ll close this as WONTFIX. Sorry. &gt; 2. The
current epiphany-runtime package doesn&apos;t make sense to me. A GUI &gt; program shipped in a package should either include or at least depend on its &gt; .desktop. It&apos;s certainly unusual. I wish we could get rid of Firefox and install the
.desktop, but I don&apos;t think it&apos;s politically possible right now. :/ Anyway, since Epiphany is both GNOME&apos;s web app runtime as well as a standalone browser, I don&apos;t see any better solution than for the desktop file to be packaged
separately. &gt; 3. Re-evaluate whether Fedora wants to ship 2 browsers by default for its &gt; GNOME Desktop. I&apos;ll add that the browser itself is less than 1 MB on top of WebKit (which we have to have anyway), so I don&apos;t see any serious
technical problem here.</thetext>
</long_desc>
<long_desc isprivate="0">
<commentid>9456530</commentid>
<comment_count>4</comment_count>
<who name="Michael Catanzaro">mcatanzaro</who>
<bug_when>2016-06-27 14:22:49 -0400</bug_when>
<thetext>(In reply to Michael Catanzaro from comment #3) &gt; I&apos;ll add that the browser itself is less than 1 MB on top of WebKit (which &gt; we have to have anyway), so I don&apos;t see any serious technical problem here. Oops, it&apos;s &lt;10
MB, not &lt;1 MB.</thetext>
</long_desc>

</bug>

</bugzilla>
